

■ amit.rambaran@gmail.com | 🛘 (647) 609 3548 | 🕈 North York, Ontario | 🗞 amitrambaran.me

Professional Summary _____

Detail conscious full stack developer with a focus on user experience and elegant design. Created and designed a cross-plant database for engineers and QA managers to increase accessibility and reduced lookup time for automobile parts by ~30%. Consistently receive great feedback from freelance clients, including job board, e-commerce and music display websites.

Work Experience

Magna International Toronto, ON

DATABASE DEVELOPER

May 2018 – August 2018

- Designed a PHP website with an MSSQL backend for 600+ actively manufactured automobile parts in order to reduce paint usage and increase accessibility for part info
- Scheduled and conducted weekly meetings with quality engineers and systems managers to obtain specifications and provide updates on the progression of the project
- Liaised with various car manufacturer dealerships in order to establish relationships and exchange confidential information

ReconnectIT Toronto, ON

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2017 - Present

- Designed a static music display website with custom CSS animations for Trilla, an upcoming hip-hop/electronic producer for the release of "Shlomo", his fifth production project
- Utilized Wordpress and various plugins to create a website and establish brand presence for Visionary Recruitment, a job recruitment agency based in Brampton
- Currently working on a professional business website with booking and Beatstars API integration for SignatureBySB, a well renowned multi-genre producer based in Toronto. Leveraging React/Redux, Gulp and Google Analytics to solve the discontinuity between him and his clients

Projects _____

Book Buddy

HTML, CSS, Node.js, SemanticUl, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, GO

A WEB APP PROVIDING AN ALL-ACCESS HUB FOR PEOPLE TO KEEP TRACK OF BOOKS READ AND RECEIVE RECOMMENDATIONS ON SIMILAR BOOKS. DESIGNED WITH AGILE METHODOLOGY IN A TEAM OF SIX.

WeatherMe

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OpenWeather API, AJAX, JSON

A DYNAMIC, RESPONSIVE WEATHER APP THAT UTILIZES THE OPENWEATHERMAP API TO DISPLAY THE CURRENT WEATHER/FIVE DAY FORECAST ASYNCHRONOUSLY.

HaverMap

HTML, CSS, Node.js, MapBox API,
Drag & Drop, Web Worker

A GEOLOCATION API BASED WEB APP THAT PROVIDES THE DISTANCE FROM YOUR CURRENT LOCATION TO A SPECIFIED LOCATION ON A VISUAL MAP.

Education _

Ryerson University

Toronto, ON

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (HONOURS)

Sep 2014 – Jun 2019

Skills

HTML CSS JavaScript React/Redux PHP AJAX jQuery Photoshop Wordpress Git Java C